# FRANCIS ADEDIRAN

London, United Kingdom · 07429 266362

francis04j@gmail.com · https://linkedin.com/in/francis.adediran @fran6\_ca

I'm Francis. I'll describe myself as a technical architect. I enjoy building and solving technical problems. My passion for software development started 15 years ago when my friends and I build a system that allows us to solve the problem of arranging a meeting without a calendar. We won an internship with that project.

From there, I went on to complete a Computer science degree with an entrepreneurship program. I've worked in an eCommerce house, user data warehouse, and financial data warehouse.

I'm currently a software management consultant at Publicis sapient focusing on business banking transformation and API management.

My primary contributions to the team are

- Putting together uses cases, sequence diagrams, architecture design records and presenting them to stakeholders.
- Implementing features and solving cross-functional problems using C#, Javascript, and BASH.
- Optimising mocking and testing frameworks that increased development-to-release throughput by 40%
- Improving applications diagnostics and insights by adding application-workflow logging, request tracing, and event sourcing.
- > Improved services' monitoring and recovery by adding health checks and circuit breakers.

## **SKILLS**

- .NET Development (C#, F#, .Net Core)
- Javascript (Node.js, React, Typescript)
- Scripting (BASH, Powershell)
- SQL, DynamoDB, Graph DB
- Testing(xUnit, Moq, Rhino mock, NCrunch)
- Cloud Development (AWS, Azure, GCP)
- Infrastructure Dev(Kubernetes, YAML, Docker)
- System Design
- Agile (Scrum/Kanban), Waterfall, SOLID, IoC, SOA, BDD, TDD

# **EXPERIENCE**

# DEC 2020 – CURRENT

# **LEAD DEVELOPER, PUBLICIS SAPIENT**

Promoted to Lead developer

## Highlights of this role are:

- Improving applications diagnostics and insights by adding application-workflow logging, request tracing, and event sourcing.
- Deploying and maintaining resources using Azure ARM templates.
- Participating in System design, business analysis, and requirement gathering.
- Creating technical documents of processes, tools, and plans.
- Reviewing codes, deployment pipelines, logs, and metrics for improvements and reporting
- Mentoring and coaching teams to establish best practices and identify concerns.
- Improving CI/CD pipelines by making them modular and resuable
- Reporting the CTO, Sponsors, and Project managers.

#### FEB 2019 - DEC 2020

## SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, LLOYDS BANK VIA PUBLICIS SAPIENT

Contracted to Lloyds banking group as a Full-stack developer to assist the company in digitising its business users' journey.

### Highlights of this role are:

- Contributed to moving their backend services to containers using Docker and Kubernetes.
- Being part of the team that initiated the use of gRPC as our microservices' intercommunication protocol.
- Developed and deployed applications using Node.js, OpenAPI schema, Express, protobuf.
- Lead a team of developers to produce ad-hoc data integration APIs using .Net Core.
- Managed team's project using Jira, Confluence, Teams, Sharepoint.
- Mentored other developers using Brown bag sessions, regular round table sessions, delegation, and hackathon.
- Maintained and upgraded the CI/CD pipelines in Azure Devops.

#### **JULY 2017 – JAN 2019**

## **SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, NOVAFORI**

Joined the company in its early stage of transitioning its infrastructure to AWS, was part of the team that did research and developed proofs-of-concept (POCs).

Worked together with the Operations team in designing and developing CI/CD pipelines and environments.

## Highlights of this role are:

• Lead by example by being initiative and available to assist other team members.

- Using AWS infrastructure (Lambda, CodePipeline, Serverless, etc) to solve business problems.
- Worked as a key part of an agile development team, taking responsibility for organising and planning my own work.
- Gained experience in using JavaScript framework (Express, React.js, Lambda/Serverless JS) to create applications
- Expanded my knowledge and usage of .Net Core framework and integrating third party APIs.
- Ensured coding standards are followed and helped to enforce good programming practices.
- Coded in C#, Typescript, React, JSON and YAML
- Gave presentations on object-oriented programming, functional programming, TDD, Design patterns, and importance of loggings.
- Gained an understanding of event-driven architecture using Service Bus or AMQP Messaging technologies.

#### **FEB 2017 – JUNE 2017**

## LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER, TOTALJOBS (STEPSTONE UK) LTD

Worked as part of the team that dealt with SEO and Search components of the TotalJobs and sister sites.

Programmed in C#, AngularJs, SQL, Python, LESS and Bash.

Highlights of these roles were:

- Helped with the integration of external APIs such Google Adwords, Lucence Search, and Stepstone Data Repo.
- Refactored existing codebase for better quality and maintainability using SOLID principles, DRY, YAGNI, and KISS.
- Gained experience in Kanban and fast-paced project delivery.
- Expanded my knowledge of SEO and SQL data tuning.
- Worked in close collaboration with product management, testers, deployment team, and other cross-functional teams.
- Gained experience giving feedback to product owners, architects, and engineering leads.
- Owned the production operation and monitoring of APIs and services via monitoring platforms

#### **APR 2016 - DEC 2016**

## **SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER,** TICKETMASTER INC.L

Joined Livenation tech team with Ticketmaster in April 2016. The projects I was worked on were tight-deadline, high-speed delivery.

Highlights of my role were:

- Using .Net Core framework with C# for the first time to create enterprise backend microservices.
- Implemented code that is modular, self-contained and observed the technical constraints on the system.

- Created technical documentation for developers and business stakeholders. Sequence diagrams, system diagrams, and architecture decision diagrams (ADR).
- Encouraged best practices such as pair programming, TDD, coding standards, and code reviews.
- Participated in the DevOps movement by helping with the integration of CI/CD tools such as Teamcity, Octopus, SonarQube, AWS deployment.
- Integrate services using Message Queue (RabbitMq) and SQL Database.
- Gained experience giving presentations and brown bag sessions.

#### OCT 2014 - FEB 2016

## **SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, FUNDASSIST LTD**

Was tasked with moving legacy VB codes to C# and legacy Winforms applications to Web Applications.

Programmed in C#, F#, VB.NET, SQL, ASP, AngularJS, Razor, and BASH.

Highlights of these roles were:

- Set up test suites using TDD with Nunit to enable Continuous Integration.
- Owned software from Inception to Deployments.
- Set up dashboards for logging and metrics analytics using Grafana and AppMetrics Prometheus.
- Encouraged continuous learning and improvement culture through the introduction of "Thursday-just-before-Friday-tech-talks", best innovation idea, and contributor awards.

#### **SEPT 2012 - SEPT 2014**

## SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, BUY4NOW(E-GROCER) LTD

Was tasked with moving legacy VB codes to C# and legacy Winforms applications to Web Applications.

Programmed in C#, F#, VB.NET, SQL, ASP, AngularJS, Razor, and BASH.

Highlights of these roles were:

- Set up test suites using TDD with Nunit to enable Continuous Integration.
- Wrote acceptance Tests using Specflow and Selenium.
- Owned software from Inception to Deployments.
- Set up dashboards for logging and metrics analytics using Grafana and AppMetrics Prometheus.
- Encouraged continuous learning and improvement culture through the introduction of "Thursday-just-before-Friday-tech-talks", best innovation idea, and contributor awards.

#### **SEPT 2010 – SEPT 2012**

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, BUY4NOW(E-GROCER) LTD**

First job out of university. Was paired with a senior developer to help with fixing bugs and dealing with user-centric issues.

Highlights of these roles were

- Maintaining frontend applications writing in C#, ASP.NET Web Forms and JQuery.
- Pair programming with senior developers.

- Reporting to testers, scrum masters, and product owners.
- Handling ad-hoc queries from customers and generating data using SQL
- Gained an understanding of SQL, Stored procedures, Triggers, Object-Oriented programming, and layered architecture.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **CURRENT**

# **AZURE SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT EXPERT, MICROSOFT**

### **MAY 2021**

# **CERTIFIED KUBERNETES APPLICATION DEVELOPER (CKAD), CNCF**

Tested my ability to design, build and debug scalable applications using Kubernetes tools and resources

### **FEB 2018**

# AWS CERTIFIED DEVELOPER ASSOCIATE, AWS

Tested my understanding of core AWS services, best practices, and proficiency.

#### SEPT 2010 - 2016

## BA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, TRINITY COLLEGE DUBLIN

Tested my understanding of core computer science principles, design patterns, and applications.

# **ACTIVITIES**

During my spare time, I enjoy cycling, playing games and travelling. I also enjoy blogging and sharing technical knowledge via tweets and short videos.